http://www.vccuonline.net/privacy-and-security

What's New? VCCU News
Privacy & SecurityOnline SecurityFraud ProtectionIdentity TheftChildren's Online Privacy Protection PolicySecurity TipsCA Consumer Privacy Act
Privacy & Security
Ventura County Credit Union is protecting your privacy. Our Annual Privacy Notice is in PDF format. In order to view and print them, you will need Acrobat Reader. If you do not have this software, you can download it for free. Just click here and follow the instructions.
Under the California Financial Information Privacy Act, State Bill 1, effective July 1, 2004, additional options are provided to you. For more information regarding this, please see our Privacy Opt Out Form.
If you are a California resident, you have specific rights regarding data collection and information sharing under the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) effective January 1, 2020.
Additional Privacy Notifications
Privacy & Security
Patriot Act Notice
Children's Online Privacy Protection Policy
Online Safety Basics
Parent/Child Agreement
VCCU's Children's Online Privacy Protection Disclosure
Other Online Information We Collect and Use
Social Media Sites
Protecting Your Information, Confidentiality, and Security
Contact Us
Privacy & Security
Patriot Act Notice
IMPORTANT INFORMATION ABOUT PROCEDURES FOR OPENING A NEW ACCOUNT
To help the government fight the funding of terrorism and money laundering activities, federal law requires all financial institutions to obtain, verify and record information that identifies each person who opens an account. In addition on legal entity accounts, we will require identification on beneficial owners and controlling person.
What this means for you: When you open an account, we will ask for your name, address, date of birth and other information that will allow us to identify you. We may also ask to see your driver's license or other identifying documents.
Back to top
Children's Online Privacy Protection Policy
Please familiarize yourself with this information so you will be able to take maximum advantage of the many products and services available.
Back to top
Online Safety Basics
Here are some basics to keep in mind when your children are online.  - Use the parental controls available on the commercial online services. These services screen public content and provide online hosts to monitor chat rooms. Check into filtering software to screen out adult sites on the Web.
- Consider placing the computer in a "family room" in your home and make use of the Internet a family activity. Check the screen periodically and let your children know that you are interested in what they are learning online.
- Ask your children where they go online, and have them show you. If your children are more familiar with the Internet than you are, let them teach you about it, you will both enjoy the lesson!
- Monitor online time. Be aware of excessive hours on the Internet.
- Make sure your children are aware of online rules. They should know never to give out their real name, address and/or telephone number, or agree to meet with someone person to person. Advise your children that some people on the Internet conceal their real age and identity. Create a list of online rules and post them by the computer.
- Monitor your modem telephone bill. Adult Bulletin Board Systems are easy to access by any communications software. Check out any unfamiliar numbers on your bill.
- Support and encourage your child's use of the Internet, and participate in new learning experiences. Acquaint yourself with their online pals and e-mail habits. Be aware of correspondence with strangers.
Back to top
Parent/Child Agreement
- I will tell my parents right away if I come across any information that makes me feel uncomfortable.
- I will not give out my address, telephone number, or the name and location of my school without my parent's permission.
- I will never agree to get together with someone I "meet" online without first checking with my parents. If my parents agree to the meeting, I will be sure that it is in a public place and bring a parent along.
- If I get a message that is mean, or makes me feel uncomfortable, I will not respond. I will log off and tell my parents. It is not my fault if I get a message like that.
Back to top
VCCU's Children's Online Privacy Protection Disclosure
The Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) was signed into law on October 21, 1998. COPPA prohibits unfair or deceptive acts or practices in collection, use or disclosure of personally identifiable information from or about children on the Internet. The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) issued the rule, 16 CFR Part 312, effective April 21, 2000. We recognize that protecting children's identities and online privacy is important and that responsibility rests with us and with parents. The personally identifiable information we collect will not be not shared or sold to third parties for any reason. Occasionally we may collect personally identifiable information from children for the purpose of contest notification, survey feedback and online communication. We do not collect any more information than is reasonably necessary for a child to participate in an activity as a condition of participation. This information is collected directly from the child and may include name, e-mail address, home address, telephone number, hobbies, or opinions. Reasonable efforts, such as letters, calls or e-mail confirmations are used to gain parental consent or notification when we communicate to children. VCCU does not disclose any of the above information to any third parties. Parents may at any time request to review the child's personal information, ask to have it deleted and refuse to allow any further collection or use of the child's information. For such requests, e-mail cumarketing@vccuonline.net, call 800.339.0496 or write to: Marketing, VCCU, 2575 Vista Del Mar Drive, Suite 100,  Ventura, CA 93001.
Back to top
Other Online Information We Collect and Use
We may collect and use other information, such as:  - Cookies: Cookies are pieces of data stored directly on the device you are using when you visit our website. Cookies allow us to collect information such as browser type, date and time spent on our website, and pages visited. We use the information for security purposes, to facilitate navigation, to display information more effectively, to personalize and enrich your experience while visiting the website, and to recognize your device to allow your use of our online services. We also gather statistical information about the usage of the website in order to continually improve the design and functionality, to monitor responses to our advertisements, to understand how customers use the website, and to assist us with resolving website questions. You can refuse to accept these cookies and most devices and browsers offer their own privacy settings for cookies. You will need to manage your cookie settings for each device and browser you use. However, if you do not accept these cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of the website and some online services. For example, we may not be able to recognize your device and you may need to answer challenge questions each time you log on. You also may not receive advertising or other offers from us that are relevant to your interests and needs.
- IP Address: Your IP Address is a number that is automatically assigned to the device that you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP). An IP Address is identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever a user visits the website, along with the time of the visit and the page(s) that were visited. Collecting IP Addresses is standard practice on the internet and is done automatically by many websites. We use IP Addresses for purposes such as calculating website usage levels, helping diagnose server problems, and administering the website.
Back to top
Social Media Sites
Ventura County Credit Union (VCCU) provides experiences on social media platforms such as Facebook®, YouTube, Twitter®, LinkedIn®, Yelp®, Google+, and others that enable online sharing and collaboration among users who have registered with them.  All social media websites referenced on the VCCU website, or on social media websites in which VCCU has a presence, are controlled and administered by a third party, are not owned or controlled by VCCU, have different privacy policies from VCCU, and this VCCU Online Privacy Notice does not apply to those sites. Any content you post on social media websites is subject to the privacy policies of those platforms. You should refer to their privacy policies to better understand your rights and obligations with regard to such content and their privacy and information sharing practices.
Back to top
Protecting Your Information, Confidentiality, and Security
We protect information we collect about you by maintaining physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards. These safeguards restrict access to your confidential information to only authorized personnel with specific need to access and utilize your information. We train our employees on how to handle your information to maintain confidentiality and privacy. To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer and system safeguards and secured files and buildings.
Back to top
Contact Us
If you have any questions regarding this Online Privacy Notice call us at 800.339.0496 or write to us at: Ventura County Credit Union
Attn: Financial Privacy
2575 Vista Del Mar Drive, Suite 100
Ventura, CA 93001
Back to top
Already a Member?
Open an additional account or apply for a loan here.
